<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>William George Cook</title><link>https://williamgeorgecook.com/</link><description>Recent content on William George Cook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>William George Cook 2022</copyright><atom:link href="https://williamgeorgecook.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://williamgeorgecook.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://williamgeorgecook.com/about/</guid><description>Hello there! Thank you for stopping by! I&amp;rsquo;m a full stack lead developer, proficient in Go, Python, and JavaScript (React, mostly).
Current lead developer at Conquer. I can only succeed if my team succeeds. Inclusive, empathetic and understanding. Forever a student and always a mentor. Hiring! On a more personal note&amp;hellip; I live in California with my wife, daughter, and pitty puppy. I volunteer at our local dog rescue by managing their IT infrastructure and fostering regularly.</description><content>&lt;h1 id="hello-there">Hello there!&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Thank you for stopping by! I&amp;rsquo;m a full stack lead developer, proficient in Go, Python, and JavaScript (React, mostly).&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Current lead developer at &lt;a href="conquer.io">Conquer&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I can only succeed if my team succeeds.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Inclusive, empathetic and understanding.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Forever a student and always a mentor.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://conquer.io/careers/">Hiring!&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="on-a-more-personal-note">On a more personal note&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I live in California with my wife, daughter, and pitty puppy. I volunteer at our local dog rescue by managing their IT infrastructure and fostering regularly. We take frequent vacations to Disneyland and Disney World in between visiting our families in the midwest and east coast. My favorite wine is a Cabernet Savingon, though I do love a really good GSM as well. Tech is my third career: I have a degree in botany and worked freelance in photo and video before landing among all of these computers.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://williamgeorgecook.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://williamgeorgecook.com/contact/</guid><description>Get In Touch LinkedIn Email</description><content>&lt;h1 id="get-in-touch">Get In Touch&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://linkedin.com/in/wgeorgecook">LinkedIn&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:web@casadecook.com">Email&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item><item><title>Highlighted Works</title><link>https://williamgeorgecook.com/showcase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://williamgeorgecook.com/showcase/</guid><description>Charity Yeti Charity Yeti aims to raise money for the Partner&amp;rsquo;s In Health maternal center of excellency in Sierra Leone. What began as a Tweet from Hank Green is growing to a platform that allows Twitter users to contribute to ending infant and mother mortality in Sierra Leone.
Meet Needs Meet Needs is a community broker program that allows for basic moderation. Through Meet Needs, people can submit needs they need met with contact information that is only available to the moderator, and the need itself is posted to the community Needs Board.</description><content>&lt;h1 id="charity-yeti">Charity Yeti&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://williamgeorgecook.com/img/logo.png" alt="Charity Yeti" title="Charity Yeti logo, with 'Charity' in purple with a yellow heart dotting the 'i', and 'Yeti' in yellow with a purple heart dotting the 'i'.">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/wgeorgecook/charityyeti">Charity Yeti&lt;/a> aims to raise money for the &lt;a href="https://www.pih.org/maternal-center-excellence?form=hankandjohn">Partner&amp;rsquo;s In Health maternal center of excellency in Sierra Leone&lt;/a>. What began as a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hankgreen/status/1186824079120011264">Tweet from Hank Green&lt;/a> is growing to a platform that allows Twitter users to contribute to ending infant and mother mortality in Sierra Leone.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="meet-needs">Meet Needs&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/wgeorgecook/meetneeds">Meet Needs&lt;/a> is a community broker program that allows for basic moderation. Through Meet Needs, people can submit needs they need met with contact information that is only available to the moderator, and the need itself is posted to the community Needs Board. People can volunteer to meet a need, and send their contact information to the moderator. The goal here is for the moderators to verify both need makers and need fulfillers and connect the two parties.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="carb-counter">Carb Counter&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/wgeorgecook/carbCounter">Carb Counter&lt;/a> is a nutritional database program that allows users to keep a bank of their common dietary items and search through them to add up the amount of carbs they&amp;rsquo;ve consumed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="github">Github&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>You can see more of my little projects and open source contributions on my &lt;a href="https://github.com/wgeorgecook">Github&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>